welcome back to six at $0.99 artificial
欢迎回到6美元人造0.99美元
general intelligence today we have mark
一般情报今天 我们有标记
raybert he is the he really doesn't need
雷伯特他是他 真的 不需要的
an introduction but we'll give him one
介绍，但我们会给他一个
anyway he's the founder and CEO CEO of
无论如何， 他是该公司的创始人兼 首席执行官
Boston Dynamics he founded the CMU like
波士顿动力，他创办了CMU 像
lab in 1980 the MIT leg lab in 1986
实验室于1980年成为麻省理工学院1986年的腿实验室
Boston Dynamics in 1992 he and his team
1992年波士顿动力公司他和他的团队
have developed some of the most amazing
已经开发出一些最令人惊叹的
robots ever built including Big Dawg
机器人曾经建造过，包括 Big Dawg
Atlas handle spot spot mini these robots
Atlas处理现货迷你这些机器人
move with the agility dexterity and even
敏捷灵巧地移动甚至是
grace that rivals and often supersedes
相媲美并经常取代的恩典
that of human movement he continues to
继续他 的人类 运动
inspire us with what robots are capable
用机器人的能力激励我们
of achieving in the real world and what
在现实世界中实现什么
physical form future intelligence
身体形成未来智力
systems may take as they become
系统可能会随着它们变成现实
integrated in our daily lives so please
集成在 我们的日常生活中，所以请
give mark a warm welcome
给予马克热烈的欢迎
[Applause]
[掌声]
this is our grand mission our aspiration
这是我们的伟大使命我们的愿望
which is to make robots that are equal
这是为了使机器人相等
to or greater than people and animals
比人或动物更大或更大
and it's you know it's a daunting
而且你知道这是一个令人生畏的事
mission because we're so good at things
任务因为我们擅长 于事物
it seems effortless you know I'm
你知道我似乎毫不费力
standing here knowing questions that I
站在这里知道我的问题
could stand here like this but a lots
可以站在这里，但很多
going on I can manipulate things I can
继续我可以操纵我能做的事情
pick up this water or I could reach in
拿起这水或者我可以进去
my pocket and use my hands with all the
我的口袋 ，用我的双手
sensors in my hands and coordinate that
我手中的传感器并协调它
and maybe most of all our perception
也许 最重要的是我们的看法
systems you know this audience has what
系统你知道这个观众有什么
is it 250 people in it or something and
在它是250 人或东西 ，
I can look out there and see every one
我可以看到那里，看到每一个
of you stabilized in space even while
你的身体在太空中稳定了
I'm moving it's it's just astounding and
我动它，它只是令人震惊 和
you know robots aren't there yet but I
你知道机器人还没有，但我
think they can be and our goal is to
认为他们 可以，我们的目标 是
keep chipping away to try and get there
不停地试着去那儿
before I get started I wanted to say
在 我开始 之前 我 想说
that I got my start in robotics here at
我得到了我的机器人开始在 这里
MIT I was a graduate student I was in
MIT我 是个研究生 我是在
the what was then called the psychology
那被称为心理学的东西
department the brain and cognitive
部门大脑和认知
sciences department but I was taking an
科学系，但我正在考虑
AI AP course just like you are and it
AI AP课程 就像你和它一样
might have been you know exactly this
可能你一直都知道这个
time of year
一年中的时间
when I followed one that my professor
当我跟随我的教授时
Burt old horn back I had so I was
Burt老喇叭 我 回来 了，所以我是
jabbering away out I'm asking him some
匆匆离开 ，我问他一些
question about this or that and we
关于这个 或那个的问题 和我们
walked back to tech square which is
走回科技广场
where the AI lab was in those days and
其中人工智能实验室是在那些日子里 和
we went up to the ninth floor and
我们去了 九楼
Russell nafse Kerr who was a guy working
Russell nafse Kerr是一个工作的人
in the lab had an arm all taken apart on
在实验室里，一只胳膊 都被拆开了
the table it was like a thousand pieces
桌子就像一千块
and I was a roboticist from that day on
从那天起我就是一名机器人专家
I swear I didn't switch my major but I
我发誓我没有切换我的 专业，但 我
you know got Burt old to be an advisor I
你知道得 伯特岁是一个顾问， 我
found a topic that had to do with
找到了一个与之有关的话题
robotics in that time it was a
机器人在那个时候它是一个
manipulation thing but eventually became
操纵的东西，但最终成了
legged thing and it was amazing you know
有腿的事情， 你知道 这太棒了
and I've never looked back
我从来没有回头
so here are some animals doing things
所以这里有一些动物做事
that are very exciting climbing around
这是非常 令人兴奋的攀爬
on very rough terrain very sure-footed
在非常崎岖的地形上非常 确定
using a mixture of their proprioception
使用他们的本体感觉的混合物
and their vision and look there's even a
他们的视野和外表甚至还有 一个
baby that probably is only a couple of
宝宝大概只有一对夫妇
months old has no trouble at all doing
月龄有 根本做 不麻烦
these things and look at the Grace and
这些东西，看看 格蕾丝和
suppleness and the fearlessness of these
柔软而 这些 无畏
animals it's amazing here are animals
这里的动物很棒，是动物
running for their lives the Gazelle is
为了生命奔跑， 瞪羚是
trying to stay alive for the next ten
试图在 接下来的十年中 保持活力
minutes and the cheetah is trying to get
分钟 和猎豹试图得到
a meal so that it can stay alive in
一顿饭， 它可以活着
general sorry and you know even people
一般抱歉，你甚至知道 人
can do things that a breath take I
可以做一些 让我喘不过气来的 事情
assume all of you were out this morning
假设今天 早上 你们都出去了
getting a little exercise climbing up
开始 有点 运动攀登
the green building that we're in now and
我们 现在所处的绿色建筑
and maybe the other places around here
也许在 这里的其他 地方
it's funny I bumped into some people
我碰到了一些人很有趣
when I came into the room who were
当我进入房间的时候
climbing the stairways I think they were
爬楼梯， 我认为他们是
going on a trek up and down them but I'd
我们上下跋涉，但我会
like to see the going outside so
喜欢看到外面所以
probably most of you have seen this
可能大多数人 都看过这个
video this is uh this is sort of where
视频这 是呃这是某种地方
we were after about ten years of work
我们经过大约 十年的工作
attempting to make machines that could
试图制造 可能的 机器
work out in the real world that were
在现实世界中锻炼身体
dynamically stabilized dynamics is a big
动态稳定动态是一个很大的问题
deal for our company and for what we do
交易我们的 公司和我们做的事情
so some active sensing and control and
所以一些主动传感和控制 和
understanding of the physics here this
在 这里了解物理学
robot has all its control onboard and it
机器人有它所有的控制 板上，它
has reflexes and sensors and this is an
有反应和传感器，这是一个
extension to a thousand-pound robot that
扩展到千磅重的机器人
could carry about 400 pounds of payload
可携带约400磅的有效载荷
and we took it all around the United
我们把一切 都 围绕着美国
States testing it in various situations
在各种情况下测试它的国家
here we have it in Virginia doing some
我们在弗吉尼亚州做了 一些
bushwhacking it's actually following a
bushwhacking 它实际上是跟着一个
person but the person is only in that of
但是这个 人只是那个人
you intermittently so it has to be able
你间歇性的，所以它必须能够
to keep track of where the person is and
保留 的，而该人是田径
deal with that and then back in good old
处理那个，然后回到旧的
Boston ten inches of snow
波士顿十 英寸 的雪
just marches right up the hill here's
就在这里山上游行吧
the cheetah now you know MIT has its own
猎豹现在你知道 麻省理工学院有自己的猎豹
cheetah this is our cheetah the people
猎豹这是我们的猎豹 人
know song Bay who was doing the MIT
知道正在做麻省理工学院的歌湾
cheetah a very dynamic machine and
猎豹一个非常有活力的机器 和
basically an experiment in seeing how
基本上是一个实验，看看如何
fast we could make something like this
快，我们可以做这样的事情
run although you notice it's on a
运行虽然你注意到它的上
parking lot so it wasn't doing this on
停车场所以它没有这样做 对
rough terrain and getting both the
崎岖的地形和两者兼得
efficiency and the speed in in the
效率和速度
context of a machine they'd also can do
他们也 可以做 的机器的上下文
rough terrain is a really big challenge
崎岖地形是一个非常大的挑战
that remains with us so this is just a
留在我们这里只是一个
snapshot of most of the robots that
大多数机器人的快照
we've built at Boston Dynamics over the
我们在波士顿动力公司建造的
years and I'm not going to talk about
多年，我不打算谈论
most of them I'm just going to talk
大部分我 只是 要谈
about the last four these are all robots
关于最后四个 这些 都是机器人
that we developed since we've been part
自从我们参与以来，我们开发了
of Google which has been the last four
谷歌是最后四个
years spot mini there's a spot mini on
年现货 迷你 有一个现货 迷你
the floor here which will demo a little
这里的楼层将演示 一点
later spot Atlas the humanoid some of
后来发现阿特拉斯人形的一些
you may remember the humanoid that we
你可能还记得我们 的人形
used in the DARPA Robotics Challenge you
用于DARPA 机器人挑战你
have one here and and then handle which
在这里有一个，然后处理哪个
is our latest version so I'll say have a
是我们的最新 版本所以我会说有一个
few words to say about each of them so
几句话， 说一下他们每个人如此
we had been developing a big dog and
我们一直在开发 一个大的狗，
those other quadrupeds that I showed you
那些我向你展示的其他四足动物
for quite some number of years and it
已经相当 多年 了
was amazing for us to find out when we
让我们知道什么时候 我们很惊讶
did this project on on spot this is the
这个项目就是 现场做 的
predecessor to that that there was still
前者仍然存在
a lot to learn and we kind of
很多东西要学，我们 种
revolutionized the hardware design and
彻底改变了硬件设计和
how the control worked and got a much
控制如何工作并得到了很多
higher level of rough terrain
更高水平的崎岖地形
performance and part of the solution to
性能和该溶液的一部分
that was to be able to decompose the
那是为了能够 分解
control problem into many separate
控制问题分成许多单独的
controllers that operated in different
操作不同的控制器
regions of state space and that allowed
国家空间的区域和允许的
us both to have programmers work on
我们都有程序员在工作
multiple solutions to the problem and
多种解决问题的方法 和
also have the complexity of each
也有 各自 的 复杂性
controller simplified by only having to
控制器通过仅具有简化的
operate in a small part of the dynamic
在 动态的 一小部分中运作
space
空间
here we've added a robot arm to the to
在这里，我们已经添加了一个机器人手臂到 到
the previous version of spot and you
以前版本的现货和你
know we believe that mobile manipulation
知道我们相信移动操作
that is manipulation when you can move
这是你可以移动时的操纵
the base is really a powerful way of
该基地是真正的强大途径
doing things now this is probably the
现在做这件事可能 就是这样
most important thing I want to show
我想展示的最重要的事情
tonight and I'll show it three different
今晚，我将展示三种不同
times the idea that we don't build
倍 ，我们不建 的想法
controllers that just do one particular
只做一个特定的控制器
thing but that they can determine where
事情，但他们可以确定在哪里
they are in the execution here's another
他们在执行这里是另一个
version of it and then adjust what
它的版本， 然后 调整什么
they're doing in order to compensate for
他们正在做的，以 补偿
disturbances in the real world I know
我知道现实世界的骚乱
this class is about AI and probably
这个课是关于人工智能的
autonomy I think that the one of the
自治我认为的一个
most important ways of getting to
前往的最重要途径
autonomy is to have the low level
自治是低水平的
implementations very robust to
实现非常稳健
disturbances so that the planning steps
扰乱使规划步骤
don't have to take care of all the
不必照顾所有的
minutiae of the details of the real
真正 的细节细节
world and that's what we've been trying
世界，这 就是 我们一直在努力的方向
to do there we've been experimenting
在那里我们一直 在试验
with doing delivery of packages to
与包裹交付
people's houses these are all employees
人民的房子这些都是员工
of Boston Dynamics so we didn't go
波士顿动力公司，所以我们没有去
crashing ordinary people's houses and it
撞毁普通人的房子和它
turns out that there's just lots of
事实证明，那里有很多
different kinds of stairways and
不同种类的楼梯和
entranceways and the robots doing very
入口和机器人做得很好
well we're up to something between
好吧， 我们之间的关系
seventy and eighty percent of of the
七十的百分之八十
kinds of stairs and access places we
各种楼梯和通道的地方我们
encounter after collecting data and
收集数据 后遇到的
making improvements and adjustments so
做出改进 和调整
I'm going to say if
我要说是否
you philosophical things or approach
你是哲学的东西 还是方法
things a lot of people think that this
事情很多人都认为这个
is the model of how a computer and a
是怎样 一 台电脑和一个 模型
robot interact that is there's the robot
机器人相互作用就是机器人
which is hardware and electronics and
这是硬件和电子产品
sensors and and then there's a computer
传感器， 然后有一台电脑
and that the computer listens to the
并且计算机 听取了
sensors on the robot and then gives it
机器人上的传感器，然后给它
instructions and tells it what to do and
说明并告诉它该做什么和
well I think that's actually going on
我认为这 实际上正在进行中
there's another part to the story which
故事的另一部分是
is that the physical world is also
是物质 世界 也
giving instructions to the robot and
给机器人指示和
that means that the energy is stored in
这意味着能量 存储在
the robot either in its Springs or in
机器人无论是在弹簧还是在弹簧中
its it's motion those are all important
它的动作一切都很重要
determinants of how the robots going to
的机器人如何 去决定
behave in the time coming forward and so
表现在未来的时间等等
we like to think in terms of designing
我们喜欢 认为在设计方面
the hardware of the robot the physical
物理 机器人 的硬件
world and the computer all as one
世界和计算机一体
holistic thing where we take into
我们考虑的整体事物
account those interactions sometimes we
有时我们会考虑这些互动
call this a harmony you know a harmonic
称这是和谐， 你知道 一个谐波
system is one usually where you have
系统通常是你 拥有的
energy oscillating back and forth almost
能量几乎来回摆动
all legged locomotion has some amount of
所有腿运动有一定量
harmony going on between potential
和谐之间潜在的和谐
energy of elevation potential energy of
海拔势能的能量
elastic deformation kinetic energy of
弹性变形 的 动能
motion and you know inverted pendulum
动作，你知道倒立摆
things and the like another part of our
事物等我们的另一部分
approach we call build it break it fix
方法我们称之为构建它打破它修复
it now I have friends who build their
现在我有朋友 建立他们的
robots and are so into the the beauty of
机器人和所以进入了美丽
what they've created that they kind of
他们创造了什么 样 的
put it on an altar and afraid of
把它放在祭坛上，害怕
actually hurting it so in fact I even
实际上我甚至 伤害了 它
have friends here at MIT that have done
麻省理工学院的 朋友 已经做过了
that where they have a gold-plated robot
他们有一个 镀金 机器人的地方
and they're afraid of taking it out into
而且他们害怕把它拿出来
the world I mean we're just the opposite
世界 我的意思是 我们正好相反
every one of our robots is designed to
我们的每一个机器人都是为了设计的
get bashed to bits we have staff who are
得到了我们有员工的位
there to fix the robot on a daily basis
那里 每天修理机器人
as we break it and I think doing that
当我们打破它，我想这样做
build it break it fix it means that
建立 它打破它修复它意味着
we're able to learn a lot from the
我们能够从 学到 很多东西
actual physical robot working in the
实际的物理机器人 的 工作
world and we can use that knowledge in
世界，我们可以使用 这些知识
order to improve the robot improve its
为了改善机器人的改进
behavior and we really like to go around
行为，我们真的很喜欢去 走一走
that loop as quickly and as we can early
尽可能快地循环，尽可能早
in the in the process and do it as many
在过程中并尽可能多地做
times as we can so here's what build it
倍， 我们 可以 因此在这里就是构建 它
break it fix it looks like this is in
打破它修复它看起来像是在
Somerville
萨默维尔
our engineers this is um a Boston driver
我们的工程师这是波士顿的司机
now this robots supposed to be using its
现在这个机器人应该使用它
visual system to avoid the trees I think
视觉系统，以避免树木，我认为
it might have fallen in love with this
它可能已经 爱上 了这个
tree
树
we don't purposely give them any emotion
我们并没有故意给他们任何情感
but boy it's hard not to see that and
但男孩很难不去看那个
here's the first time we tested the the
下面是我们第一次测试的
push response to this robot hey did you
推动对这个机器人的反应 嘿，你做到了
hear that
听说
that's the new guy's car so some guy we
这是新人 的车，所以有些人 我们
just started that week Trent had $5,000
就在那个星期开始， 特伦特有 5000美元
which we paid for in in repairs to his a
我们在他的修理中付出了代价
vintage BMW so the last thing sort of
复古宝马这样的最后一件事排序
about philosophy is long-term versus
关于哲学是长期的
short-term you know our company is 25
短期 你知道我们 公司是25
years old and we've mostly been a
岁，我们大多是一个
long-term robotics company that is we're
我们是长期的机器人公司
interested in moving the boundary
有意移动边界
forward in what what robots can do and
向前推进机器人可以做什么和
we're interested in you know making it
我们对 你有兴趣 了解 它
so robots meet the dream of being the
所以机器人满足了成为的梦想
equal or better than people and animals
等于或优于人和动物
but now we've started function
但现在我们已经开始运作了
[Music]
[音乐]
okay we still on can you hear me but
没关系，我们仍然能听到我 ，但
lately we've started to realize that
最近我们开始意识到 这一点
some of our robots have enough
我们的一些机器人已经足够了
capability that maybe it's time to try
可能是时候 尝试了
and productize them and we will learn a
并产品化他们，我们将学习一个
lot by doing that too one of the things
通过做那 件事 也很多
for instance that I've always claimed is
比如 ，我一直声称 是
that we always spent a lot of money on
我们总是花很多 钱
building our robots in them and use that
在他们身上建造我们的机器人 并使用 它
as a competitive advantage that is DARPA
作为DARPA的竞争优势
was a frequent funder of us DARPA always
是我们的经常资助机构DARPA 总是
said let's take money out of the
说让我们拿钱出来的
equation and just figure out you know
方程式，只是弄清楚你知道
how to get the solution and then worry
如何获得 解决方案 ，然后担心
about getting the cost down later so I
关于 以后 降低成本 所以我
always assumed and argued that once we
我们总是假设并争辩说
get a robot doing things that are
得到一个机器人做事
interesting then you can go and redesign
有趣的是 你可以去重新设计
it to make it lower cost well we're
它，使其成本更低 以及我们
going we're going to test that because
去我们要 测试的是因为
it might not be true it might be that
它可能不是真的
we've designed ourselves into an
我们把自己设计成了一个
expensive corner and that it might be
昂贵的角落， 它可能是
too late but the robot that was showing
为时已晚，但正在展示的机器人
a little bit is much significantly cost
一点点是非常显着的成本
reduced from the prototype of it and
从原型中减少了
it'll be interesting to see whether we
这将是有趣 的， 看看 我们是否
could get it down to the kind of prices
可以把它降到那种价格
that are useful so this is just a
这是有用的所以这只是 一个
picture again of the idea of aiming long
再次瞄准瞄准的想法
but also aiming short and I think it's
但也瞄准短，我认为是
going to be a challenge to see whether
看是否是一个挑战
we can keep the culture of the company
我们可以保持公司的文化
to support both of these directions
支持这两个 方向 的
because people manufacturing stuff have
因为人制造的东西 有
a different mindset than people trying
与 人们尝试不同的心态
to get out to the future horizons and
走出 未来的视野和道路
it's going to be a challenge to keep
保持这将是一个挑战
both those kinds of people happy here's
这两类人都很开心
some of the things that some of the
一些事情的 一些
kinds of applications you can look at
各种各样的 应用程序 ，你可以看看
based on modest technical capabilities
基于适度的技术能力
I've shown mobility and manipulation
我表现出了移动性和操控性
here but you could put cost reliability
在这里，但你可以把成本可靠性
there's many things that could be on
有许多事情可以发生
these axes
这些轴
you know entertainment like robots and
你知道像机器人这样的娱乐活动
theme parks is something that I think we
主题公园是我认为我们的东西
should be able to do I already talked
应该可以做我已经 说过了
about home delivery I think home
关于送货上门 我觉得回家
delivery is waiting for self-driving
交货正在等待自驾车
cars to get all the way there self
汽车一路走来 自我
driving trucks and once they do then we
驾驶卡车，一旦他们这样做，我们
will be working on getting it from the
将努力 从中 获取 它
truck to the to the home logistics
卡车到家庭物流
there's about a trillion boxes moved
有 大约一万亿箱移动
every year around the world and most of
每年都在世界各地和大部分地区
it's done by hand and so there's really
它是手工完成的，所以确实如此
a big opportunity to having robots help
让 机器人帮助的大好机会
with moving those trillion boxes
移动那些万亿箱
security which could mean either
安全可能意味着
commercial security like patrolling your
商业安全，如巡逻 你的
shopping center or the military type
购物中心或军事 类型
security construction a lot of people
安全建设很多人
have been coming to us with their
我们和他们一起来找我们
construction applications asking if we
施工申请询问我们
can help and you know I'm not going to
可以帮助你，你知道我不会
talk about it now but if afterwards you
现在谈谈它，但 如果事后你
want to ask about that I can fill you in
我 想问一下 ，我可以告诉你
a little more and I think this is really
多一点，我 认为这是真的
the ultimate home run application care
最终的 本垒打应用程序 护理
for the elderly and the disabled I used
我用过 的老人和 残疾人
to say that I wanted to have robots that
地说， 我 想有机器人 ，
would help me take care of my my parents
会帮助我 照顾我的 父母
and older people but I realize now that
和老年人， 但我现在 意识到
it's probably going to be my children
它可能会成为我的孩子
using them to help take care of me but
用它们来帮助照顾我但是
you guys all you're all a little bit
你们 所有 你们都一点点
younger and I think there'll be a time
年轻， 我认为会有一段时间
when you could use robots to help make
当你可以使用机器人来 帮助制作
your parents lives better now some of
你的父母现在生活得更好一些
you may think that your parents don't
你可能认为你父母 没有
want that but I think it's a complex
想要那个，但我觉得 这很复杂
question we've seen some surveys that
问题我们已经看到了一些调查
say that you know people aren't totally
说你知道人不 完全
happy with the idea of their kids taking
对孩子们 的 想法很满意
care of them on a moment-by-moment basis
一点一点地照顾他们
and I think there's going to be an
而且我认为 会有一个
opportunity for doing something but
做某事的 机会 但是
technically this is still a ways off
从技术上讲，这 仍然是一个方法
it's it's a tough thing okay let's get
这是一件很难的事情， 好吧，让我们得到
back to the robots
回到机器人
spot Mini is a robot that weighs about
点赠送是 重约 一个机器人
60 pounds that previous spot weighed
前一个位置称重60磅
about 180 pounds this one weighs about
这个重约 180 磅
60 pounds and here's some Anatomy it's
60磅，这里的一些解剖 它的
got an arm with five degrees of freedom
有一个手臂 五个自由度
each leg has three degrees of freedom
每条腿 都有 三个自由度
it's got about a 500 watt our battery
我们的电池大约有500瓦
batteries for these things are a
这些东西的电池是一个
challenge because you know
挑战， 因为 你知道
can have consumer products like electric
可以有电动等消费品
drills that have relatively small
钻头比较小
batteries and then there's electric cars
电池然后有电动车
that have big batteries and there's not
有大电池但没有
really much available in between so
两者之间 真的很有用
we've done a lot of work on the battery
我们在电池方面做了很多工作
technology for these things to make them
制造这些东西的技术
safe and reliable and hot swappable and
安全可靠，热插拔
things like that then there's radios and
像这样的东西然后有收音机和
computers the previous version had three
计算机以前的 版本有三个
quad core i7s this one has two we're
四核i7s这个有两个我们
trying to cut back on the cost and then
试图削减成本然后
there can be some sensors lidar s stereo
可以有一些传感器 激光雷达立体声
and the like so you can see spot minis a
而 像这样你 可以看到现场一个迷你
little bit smaller than spot this isn't
比现实小一点， 这不是
a real house and those aren't real
一个真正的房子，那些不是真实的
people those are engineers this is
那些人是 工程师
inside of a warehouse we have out on 128
仓库 里面 ，我们有出去 128
where we've built the house you can see
在那里我们建造了你能看到的房子
that they don't we don't mind scuffing
他们不是我们 不介意磨损
up the walls here and there is a lot of
在这里的墙壁 ，有很多
scuffing that happens some of you may
你们中的一些人可能会发生严重的磨损
recognize ACTU Kowski who's a an MIT
认识到麻省理工学院的ACTU Kowski
alum and he's again disturbing the robot
明矾，他又一次打扰了机器人
here the robots using its vision to do
这里的机器人用它的愿景去做
some stepping stone type operations and
一些踏脚石式的操作和
I think gene is going to talk a little
我认为基因会谈 一点
bit more about this in a couple of
位 更多关于此的情侣
minutes and here's a case where it's
分钟，这里有一个 情况是
doing stepping stones on real stones and
在真石上做垫脚石
it's keeping its balance figuring out
它保持其平衡搞清楚
where to put the feet and again this
在哪里放脚和再次这个
robot only has stereo looking out the
机器人只有立体声看着
front whereas this one has stereo on all
前而这其中 有立体声所有
four sides
四边
now one of the cool things about animals
现在关于 动物的一件很酷的事情
is that they have these stabilization
是他们有这些稳定
mechanisms for their sensors that was a
他们的传感器的机制是一个
real chicken no robotics involved and
真正的鸡没有 机器人参与和
here's our attempt to show that these
这是我们试图证明 这些
this robot can do the same sort of thing
这个机器人可以做同样 的事情
and if you think about it when you're
如果你想的话，如果你想的话
manipulating you really want the hand to
操纵你真的想要手
be stabilized in space and so you'd like
在太空稳定，所以你想
the body to be able to kind of
身体能 种
coordinate with the hands so that you
用手协调你
can concentrate on what the world
可以专注于世界
real-world task is man
现实世界的 任务是人
you guys didn't pick up the banana peel
你们没有拿起 香蕉皮
huh so our concept for the spot mini
呵呵所以我们 的现场迷你 概念
product is to make a platform it's sort
产品是做一个平台， 它的排序
of the we're thinking of it like the
的，我们正在考虑它像
Android of robots so with Android
机器人，随着Android的安卓
there's a hardware platform and then
然后是硬件平台
there's a software platform and then
然后是一个软件平台
developers third-party developers create
开发人员第三方开发人员创建
their own apps that use the platform so
他们自己的应用程序使用该平台
we've made this spot so that there's a
我们已经创造了这个位置， 所以有一个
place to mount hardware on the robot but
在机器人上安装硬件但是
there's also an API to program it
还有一个API 来编程它
through and then there's a facility to
通过，然后有一个设施
have additional computing external to
有额外的计算外部
the robot and we're working with third
机器人，我们正在与第三个 工作
parties to develop their own
双方发展 自己
applications that run on the platform
在平台上运行的应用程序
this is a video that we haven't been
这 是我们还没有去过的视频
able to release publicly please don't
能够公开发布请不要
tape it and show it because I can't I'll
将它录下并展示， 因为我 不能
explain later if you want to know why
如果你想知道原因，请稍后解释
not but this is just a revealing that we
不是，这只是 我们的一个启示
do have an arm on the new version of
确实有一个新版本 的手臂
spot
点
it's using a camera in the hand to find
它正在用手中的相机找到
the the door handle this robot doesn't
这个机器人没有的门把手
weigh a lot so it has to use tricks to
重量很重，所以必须使用技巧
keep the door open so that's why puts
保持门打开，这就是 为什么放
his foot in the door and here again we
他的脚踏在门口， 又来了我们
want to show that the we've made the
想表明我们已经做到了
solution robust to certain kinds of
解决方案对某些类型的强大
disturbances so Andy there Andy sitting
骚扰所以安迪在那 里安迪坐着
over here is pushing on the door pushing
在这里推着推门
on the hand the robot keeps track of how
在手上机器人跟踪如何
far how much progress that's made in
远了多大的进步 是在制造
doing its task it's so it's so smart it
做它的任务它是如此 聪明
even kicks that that shell out of the
甚至踢那个贝壳出来的
way now that was a total accident and
现在 ，这是一个完全意外的方式
now it's just going back to try again
现在它又回去 再试 一次
okay and then this is a demo of autonomy
好的 ，然后这 是一个自治的演示
here the robot has in a previous session
这里机器人 在之前的会话中
we've taken it around the lab this is
我们已经把 它 带到 了实验室
Boston Dynamics taking them around the
波士顿动力公司将他们带到 了
lab and recorded visual data that could
实验室和记录的可视数据
be used for navigation and it's using
用于 导航 和它的使用
its stereo to match up features in the
它的立体声匹配功能
environment so that it can navigate and
环境， 以便 它可以浏览和
go where it had gone in the previous on
去了之前的地方
the previous path so there's no one
以前的路径所以没有人
driving it for this it's all autonomous
为此 而驾驶它 全部都是自主的
that was outside my office every day
这是每一天我的办公室外
around noon the robot seems to show up
中午左右机器人似乎出现了
and I hear it pausing out there I don't
我听到 它暂停了我没有
know why it turned there sometimes it
知道为什么它有时会转向那里
comes up with a solution that isn't in
提出了 一个不 存在 的解决方案
here you'll see another one it comes up
在这里，你会看到它出现的另一个
with a solution that isn't quite
解决方案并不完全
what you call is an optimization but it
你所说的是一种优化，但它
does it does get a solution so we're
它确实得到了解决方案， 所以我们
pretty excited by this we call this
非常兴奋，我们称之为
patroller out and we're working on
巡逻了，我们正在努力
developing a lot of software to support
开发 大量 软件来支持
it to make it so that other people can
它是为了让 别人能够 做到这一点
capture a patrol route and then execute
捕获巡逻路线然后执行
them on a on a routine basis and then do
他们在例行的基础上然后做
two other tasks while they're on the on
他们正在进行的另外两项任务
the patrol route Seth you're on so we're
塞特的巡逻路线你在 我们 身边
at will do a demo of spot mini so for
在 会做点小所以对于演示
these for this demo Seth's got a
对于这个演示，Seth有一个
joystick and he's telling it the speed
操纵杆，他告诉它 的速度
to go in the forward direction and
向前迈进
turning but the robots doing all its own
转动，但机器人 自己做
gate selection coordination of legs
门的选择 协调
balance obviously so the robot has a
显然平衡，所以机器人有一个
bunch of different gates it can walk
一堆不同的大门，它可以走
here it's doing one leg at a time it can
在这里， 它可以 一次做一条腿
trot I know you do whatever gates you
小跑我知道你做任何事都可以帮助你
want except he's got to use a selective
想除了他有 使用 选择性
so here's trotting which is diagonal
所以这里是对角线的小跑
pairs of legs it can do pacing which is
它可以做起搏的双腿
lateral pairs of legs to get working
侧腿对开始工作
together I have to tell you in the
我必须在一起告诉你
earliest days of me being involved in
我参与的最早的日子
legged locomotion
腿部运动
I thought gait was a big deal but it's
我觉得步态很重要 但是确实如此
really kind of a small thing and I don't
真的很小， 我没有
think it's central to what matters which
认为这是中央 对哪些事项 该
is support stability propulsion and
是支持稳定推进和
things like that I'm gonna wrap up
这样的事情，我要结束
shortly I just thought I'd say a couple
不久我只是想我会说一对
of words about the mechanical side you
关于 机械 方面的话
know the Atlas is a new version of a
知道Atlas是 一个 新版本
humanoid I know some of you worked with
人形我知道你们有些人合作过
the DARPA Robotics Challenge humanoid
DARPA 机器人挑战人形机器人
which was a big hulking thing that we
这对我们来说是个笨重的事情
made and this is a much more svelte one
制作，这是一个更苗条的
and the way we got there was to work on
我们到那里的方式就是努力
the elements of the mechanical design to
机械设计的要素
take advantage of 3d printing and some
利用3d打印和一些
optimization and we did we focused on
优化，我们专注于
two or three different things one is
一两个或三个 不同的东西
making some of the leg parts where we
把一些 腿部分放在我们身边
embed hydraulic pathways hydraulic
嵌入液压通道液压
actuators places for valve mounts and
阀座和阀门的执行器位置
filters and things like that into the
过滤器和类似的东西进入
leg and this is what that looks like
腿，这就是看起来像
there's a single upper leg part that
有一个 单腿上部
incorporated about 15 or 20 different
纳入约15或20种不同的
separate components in the previous
以前的单独组件
design which made it lighter more
设计让它更轻盈
compact and higher strength to weight
结构紧凑，重量更高
ratio we also developed a hydraulic
比例我们还开发了液压
power unit which takes many components
功率单元，需要很多组件
the thing on the left are the components
左边的东西是 组件
as separate ones and we were able to
作为独立的人，我们能
print up parts that integrated them so
打印出集成它们的部件
that there was a motor a pump inside of
这有一个电机的内部 泵
a motor an accumulator reservoir valves
电动机蓄电池储气阀
filters and those things and we shrunk
过滤器和那些东西，我们缩小了
it down so that the robot could be
它下来，以便 机器人可以
smaller and lighter and using that
更小更轻，使用它
approach we went from about a 375 pound
接近我们从大约375英镑
DRC robot to a 190 pound robot and then
DRC机器人然后到190磅的机器人
the current one is about 165 pounds now
目前 现在 大约165磅
this picture might lead you to believe
这张照片可能会让你 相信
that I'm advertising myself is only
说 我自己的广告 只
weighing 165 pounds and I'm fortunately
体重165磅 ，我很幸运
that's not true but I'm working on it
那 不是真的， 但我正在研究它
but it is close to my size and weight
但它接近 我的 体重 和 体重
and I don't know I don't think we have
而且我不知道我 认为我们没有
this out as a video here's some robot
这是一个视频，这里是一些机器人
behavior that uses whole body motion
使用全身运动的行为
meaning the mobility base plus the arms
意思是 流动性 基础加上武器
plus the torso are all combining in
加上躯干都在结合
order to handle these these boxes it's
为了处理这些这些盒子
using vision with the QR codes to
使用QR码的视觉
simplify the task here we're trying to
这里简化任务，我们正在 努力
go at human speeds of operation and so
按照人的操作速度等等
the robot searches for a box using its
机器人使用它搜索一个盒子
vision
视力
I think that I think that was the only
我认为我认为 这是唯一的
take we ever got with both robots
我们用两个机器人
working together and you know one of the
一起工作，你知道的一个
problems with YouTube is everybody's
与 YouTube的问题是大家的
already seen what you've been up to by
已经看到你一直在做什么
the time you get it go around to give a
你得到它的时间去给一个
talk so I imagine most of you have seen
说话， 所以我想 你们 大多数人 都看过了
this but here's a parkour robot we're
这是我们的跑酷机器人
working on where we've actually
在我们实际的地方工作
strengthened the hips so that it can do
加强臀部，使其能够做到
a little bit more jumping and and it's a
多一点跳跃，这是一个
kind of interesting that we've been
我们去过的那种有趣的事情
interested in making a robot a little
有兴趣 制造一个机器人
bit like the humanoid that has less
有点像人形的东西少了
degrees of freedom fewer degrees of
自由度较低
freedom and the simpler and we designed
我们设计的自由和 简单
this robot and the ultimate version of
这个机器人的终极版
this we'll have about 10 joints whereas
这个 我们将有大约 10个关节， 而
the humanoid had 28 and have many many
人形机器人有28个，有很多
of the same capabilities we have some
我们 有一些 相同的 能力
use cases for this that I'm not going to
用例 ，我不 会这样做
talk about today but this robot can lift
今天 谈谈 ， 但这个机器人 可以解除
heavy loads it has a relatively small
重载它有一个相对较小的
footprint given what its strength is so
考虑到其实力如此，足迹
the way things are done in logistics now
事情的方式， 现在在 做 物流
is to use big robot arms that take up a
是使用大型机器人手臂
lot of floor area or heavy and we're
我们 的地板面积很大或很重
looking at ways of using a robot like
看看如何使用机器人
this one not exactly this we it's sort
这个不完全是我们的排序
of any evolution of this design in order
这个设计的任何进化 顺序
to do logistics operations so I want to
我想做物流业务
make a pitch to you Boston Dynamics is
波士顿动力公司为你 做一个投球
hiring and I hope some of you will apply
招聘，我希望你们中的一些人 会申请
for a job there these are how many is it
在那里工作这些 是多少
6 x 3 these are 18 MIT alum that
6 x 3这些 是18 MIT明矾
currently work at the company many of
目前在该公司工作很多
them for many years so I'm sort of
他们多年 ，所以我有点
making the point that these people are
指出这些人是谁
happy they're just like just like you
很高兴他们就像你一样
could be and I hope you'll look at our
可能是，我希望你看看我们的
website
网站
and see what we're what we're looking
看看我们正在寻找 什么
for and considerate so I'm just gonna
为了和体贴，所以我要去
wrap up by talking about you know I used
通过谈论你知道我用过来结束
to be a professor here and at Carnegie
成为 一个教授 ， 在这里，并在 卡内基
Mellon and when I was the professor
梅隆和我当 教授
we used to mostly wrote papers and we
我们以前主要是写论文和我们
were excited by you know how many papers
你知道有多少论文很兴奋
we could write and how many people cited
我们可以写，有多少人引用
them in their papers but as a company
他们在论文中，但作为一家公司
guy instead of papers I think we count
家伙而不是纸张我认为我们算数
YouTube hits and instead of citations
YouTube点击而不是引用
here I want to tell you what this is but
在这里，我想告诉你这是什么
most of you probably know
大多数人可能都知道
so now we count now we count spoofs
所以现在我们算上我们算欺骗了
instead of citations and I'm happy to
而不是引用，我很高兴
say that we're doing great we have about
说我们做得 很好 ，我们有关于
about two dozen BigDog spoofs here's
这里有 大约 二十几个BigDog恶搞
four of them and the upper left is in
其中四个，左上角是
Akihabara Japan the upper right is a Los
秋叶原日本右上角是洛杉矶
Angeles online television show
在线 电视节目
it's the Netherlands on the lower left
左下角是荷兰
and I guess that's Appalachia on the
而且我猜那是阿巴拉契亚山脉
right the poor kid doesn't even have a
对， 这个可怜的孩子 甚至没有
friend to to be in his movie well what
朋友要在他的电影中做什么
about what about Atlas can you hear that
关于阿特拉斯，你能听到什么吗？
[Music]
[音乐]
here's it here's another one
这里是它这里的另一个
[Applause]
[掌声]
so we have we have a big crew working on
所以我们有一大群人在工作
all these projects you've you've gotten
所有你，你已经 得到了这些项目
to meet a couple of them here but it's
在这里见到他们中的几个， 但它是
really quite a team in a an absolute
真的是一个 绝对 的团队
pleasure to work with so anyway thank
很高兴有 这么 反正谢谢 合作
you
您
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Music]
[音乐]
thanks for the presentation it was
谢谢你的介绍是
amazing
惊人
what sort of physics simulation like if
什么样的物理模拟， 如果
any do you have in your robots and do
你 在机器人中有没有做过
you really think that like with the
你真的认为喜欢和
current trend of neural networks we can
我们可以在神经网络的当前趋势
just like do end-to-end modeling of
就像端到端的 建模一样
these robots with like without any sort
这些机器人有一样 没有任何类型
of notion of physics but just like
物理概念，但就像
neural networks so we have simulators
神经网络， 所以我们有 模拟器
that we've worked on for a long time
我们已经工作 了很长一段时间
very detailed in some cases validated
在某些情况下非常详细的验证
validated me and compare the behavior of
验证了我并比较了它的 行为
the simulator to the physics of ground
地面物理模拟器
truth and you know I think they're
真相，你知道我认为他们是
important for our work and we use them
对 我们的 工作很重要，我们使用它们
frequently but the end to end doesn't
经常但端到端却没有
ring quite true
戒指相当真实
usually the when we use simulation the
通常是我们使用模拟的时候
user is knowledgeable about the
用户对此有所了解
trade-offs between doing a physical
做 身体 之间的权衡
experiment and doing a simulated
实验并做模拟
experiment and they're usually getting
实验， 他们通常会得到
at some specific where specific setup
在特定 设置的某些特定 位置
question rather than the idea that you
问题而不是 你的想法
start at one end you know - at least in
从一开始你 知道 - 至少在...
our experience trying to simulate all
我们尝试模拟所有的经验
the subtleties of the hydraulic actuator
液压执行器的细微之处
back lashing gears flexibility
背绑式齿轮的 灵活性
you know the non rigidity in the
你知道在非刚性
components that's a big undertaking and
组件，这是一项伟大的事业和
usually so so distracting that you can't
通常如此分散注意力，你不能
really get on with with what you're
我真的相处你的
doing so I think we use experiment for
这样做我认为我们使用实验
those subtleties and we use simulation
那些微妙之处我们使用模拟
for bigger level dynamics questions hey
对于更大的动态问题 嘿
would you say mechanical concerns or
你会说 机械问题 吗？
computational capability is more of a
计算能力更多的是
difficulty in terms of determining how
难以确定如何
quickly you can perform tasks with the
很快你就可以用 了
robots you know we like to say that
机器人你 知道我们喜欢这么 说
they're equally important we we now
我们现在和他们同样重要
although we didn't start out this way we
虽然我们没有这样开始 我们
now have equal strength in our groups in
现在在我们的团队中拥有同等的实力
the mechanical design and implementation
机械设计和实施
and in the software and controls and
在软件和控件和
sensing and I think you know they all
传感，我想你都知道
matter I think if you try and get by
我想 如果你 试着过来的话
with just marginally designed hardware
只有略微设计的硬件
you don't get my
你没有得到 我的
experimental time in because the things
实验时间因为事物
broken all the time so even though we
尽管我们已经 打破了 所以
are rough on our machines they mostly
在他们 的 机器上他们大多是粗糙的
keep working because because we've put a
继续工作，因为我们已经放了一个
lot of you know attention to detail and
很多人都知道 对细节的 关注
how they're designed but you know
它们是如何 设计 但你知道的
there's still that I think perception is
还有我认为感知是
still a tall pole in the tent certainly
肯定还是帐篷里的高杆
if you want a rival human perception I
如果你想要一个竞争对手的 人类感知我
don't think we're you know were anywhere
不要以为我们是你知道，我们在任何地方
near there I think the self-driving car
附近还有我觉得 自驾车
stuff is helping there's a lot of
东西是帮助有很多 的
interesting things happen there I think
我想 有趣的 事情发生在那里
specialized Hardware skating you know
你知道的专业硬件滑冰
Asics and and things that could help but
ASIC和和的事情，可以帮助 ，但
you know it's it's all still needed so
你知道这一切都还需要
you guys have developed like various
你们发展得像各种各样
components that all kind of they'll come
所有他们都来的组件
together to build one robot have you
一起建造一个机器人有你
seen applications for any of these
看到任何这些的申请
separate components elsewhere so organic
其他地方的组件是有机的
design for example for the Atlas maybe
例如为Atlas设计的 可能
prosthetics or hip replacements or
假肢或髋关节置换术或
something like that because there seems
这样的东西，因为 似乎
to be a lot of development going on and
是 怎么回事 了很大的 发展 和
then individually as well as the big
然后单独 以及 大
picture I mean you're asking a very good
图片我的意思是你问得很好
question there's a question in case
问题有一个问题，以防万一
people couldn't hear is aside from value
人们听不到的是价值
to the whole robot of the components
整个机器人的组件
we're making are the components useful
我们正在制作有用的组件
some other way and you know the place
另一种方式，你知道这个地方
where we think it's probably most true
我们 认为这 可能是最真实的
is the specialized hydraulic components
是专业的液压元件
we've made servo valves and the HPU
我们制造了伺服阀和HPU
I'm sure we could sell them into other
我相信我们可以将它们卖给 其他人
industry I as a company focus question
行业我作为公司的焦点问题
though that's really what it comes to do
虽然那真的是它要做的事情
we really want to be doing that will
我们真正想要做 的是意志
that absorb too much time and attention
吸收太多时间和注意力
and personnel or do we want to you know
和人员或我们想要你知道
our heart is really in building you know
我们的心真的在建造你知道
future generations of robots so I think
我认为， 未来几代 机器人
we're going to probably stay there okay
我们将 可能呆在那里好
thanks
谢谢
I was wondering have you done any
我想知道你做过什么
research in regards to getting the
有关 获得 的研究
robots to perform tasks involving direct
机器人执行涉及直接的任务
physical contact with humans
与人类的身体接触
I can only the only thing we've done is
我 只能 我们做 的唯一的 事情是
we've done teleoperation which is not
我们已经完成了远程操作
what you mean where we have a human
你是什么意思我们有一个人
moving in the robot you know copying
移动你知道复制的机器人
which is very interesting because you
这是非常有趣的，因为你
can see that that's a way of showing how
可以看到，这是 展示如何 的 一种方式
fast the robot can be and how
快速的机器人可以和如何
coordinated it can be using a human and
协调它可以使用人和
for part of the computing but we have we
对于部分计算， 但我们有
don't have them interacting with people
不要让 他们与 人 交往
I guess the closest is we once did a
我想最接近的是我们曾经 做过的
thing where a person and a robot picked
一个人和一个机器人 挑选的东西
up a stretcher and work together to pick
担架和一起工作来 挑选
up the stretcher but they weren't
担架， 但他们不是
touching each other they were going
他们正在接触彼此
through the stretcher material
通过担架材料
do we have plans ah you know we're
我们有计划 吗啊你知道我们是
really to be honest we're really
说实话，我们真的很棒
struggling with coming up with some
努力想出一些
strong concepts for safety even without
即使 没有强大的安全概念
doing that you know robots it's you know
这样 你知道机器人你就知道了
your first reactor stree action and how
你的第一个反应堆 stree行动和如何
you make a robot safe if there's a
如果有的话，你可以让机器人安全
problem don't really work very well you
问题不是 真的 很好用 你
can't freeze the robot you have to find
无法冻结你 必须找到的机器人
some you have to keep them going find a
有些你必须让他们去寻找一个
way to get into a safer state so I think
我 认为，进入一个更安全的状态的方式
having them in contact with people is
让他们与 人 接触 是
just going to be harder so eventually we
只是要 硬得多，因此最终我们
want to to help you know to carry lift
想帮你知道搭载电梯
the elderly and things like that but
老人之类的东西，但
we're not there yet my questions about
我们还没有实现我的问题 有关
the relative rates of progress in
的进展相对速率
robotics and machine intelligence so an
机器人和机器智能 这样一个
economist might maybe measure it by
经济学家也许可以用它来衡量
seeing how much money is going into
看到多少钱是 进入
computing hardware versus arms and leg
计算硬件与手臂和腿部
sensors and actuators that kind of thing
传感器和执行器那种东西
so on one impossible scenario the the
所以在一个不可能的场景 中
machine intelligence rushes ahead and
机器智能冲向前方
the robots progressing more slowly
机器人进展 得更慢
because of kind of slow build test cycle
因为 那种 缓慢的构建测试周期的
basically it's their real-world things
基本上这是 他们的真实世界
it's not so easy to get a rapid build
它不是那么容易 得到 了快速的构建
test cycle with a robot and in and in
测试周期与机器人和在和
the other scenario the robots more
另一种情况是机器人更多
advanced than the machine intelligence
先进的机器智能
because machine intelligence is just
因为机器智能 是 公正的
such a conceptually difficult problem so
这样一个概念上难以解决的问题
in one scenario the machines are telling
在一种情况下，机器正在讲述
the humans what to do in the other
人类在另一方面要做什么
scenario that he
场景， 他
telling the machines watch do if you
告诉机器看你做的事
like so do you have any kind of
像你这样，你有什么样的
perspective on that whole issue of them
对整个问题的看法
is that the machine intelligence folk
是机器智能民间
going to rush ahead being what's the
匆匆忙忙 去做 什么
guys struggling behind or the robots
伙计们在背后挣扎着机器人
going to get there before the massive
要在大规模之前到达那里
problem and machine intelligence gets
问题和机器智能 得到
solved or maybe somewhere in the middle
解决了或者可能在中间的某个地方
I think let's see I don't know exactly
我想我们看到的确不完全清楚
what you mean by machine intelligence
你的意思是机器智能
are you talking about
你在说什么？
you know having Google do better search
你知道让谷歌做更好的搜索
computation in general so I start I
计算一般所以我开始我
talked about economists measuring
谈到 经济学家测量
sensors actuators and compute Hardware
传感器执行器和计算 硬件
so that's the kind of thinking about
这就是那种想法
yeah I think that it's always been a
是的，我认为它一直是一个
misconception that the hardware
误以为硬件
components by themselves constitute
组件本身构成
progress in intelligence or in robot
智力或机器人的进步
behavior they're I think they're
行为他们是我认为 他们是
important ingredients but by themselves
重要的成分，但他们自己
you know when I was a graduate student
你知道我什么时候是研究生
here I can remember reading an ad for an
在这里， 我记得 为一个广告 阅读
optical character recognition system and
光学字符 识别系统和
what the ad said was you know we have
广告说的是你知道的
camera we have a thing for holding the
相机我们有一个持有的东西
paper you're looking at all you have to
纸，你正在看你所需要的一切
do is write the software so it was all
do是编写软件 所以它就是全部
done except for you got to write the
完成除了你必须写的
software and you know it's the the whole
软件，你知道 这是整体
problem was there so I don't know if I'm
问题在那里所以我不知道我是不是
answering your question
回答你的问题
you know robotics is hard I think it
你知道机器人技术很难我 想
feels like we're making progress if you
感觉就像我们正在取得进步
keep pushing we keep making progress
继续推动我们不断进步
it's not like there's an e and the curve
它不像是e 和曲线
that we've hit but I also think that the
我们已经击中 但我也认为
rest of the AI world is making a good
在AI世界其他地区正在制定 好
progress too and it's fun being a part
进步也 很有趣成为一个部分
of it
它
hi I
嗨， 我
my question is mostly related to
我的问题主要 与...有关
security so since you are productizing
因为你是产品化的安全性
your robots now there has been research
你的机器人现在有 研究
on Leiter's mainly where you could spoof
在莱特的主要是你可以欺骗的地方
a lidar and
激光雷达和
and the sensor basically cannot see
而传感器基本上看不到
anything so are you looking into that as
你还在 考虑那样的 事情
well taking into consideration these
好好考虑 这些
awesome robots that you're building
你正在建造的令人敬畏的机器人
could be in let's say you know defense
可以说让你知道防守
you know working for the defense as well
你也知道 为防守 工作
so those are like really harsh
所以这些 都是 真的一样苛刻
environments yeah I mean these are very
环境是啊我的意思是这些 非常
hard problems you know if someone if if
如果有的话，你知道的难题
an intelligent adversary wants to trick
一个聪明的对手想要欺骗
the robot it's not all that hard these
机器人这些并不是那么难
days you know where we're working
你知道我们在哪里工作的日子
probably the other end of the problem
可能是问题的另一端
you know trying to do the basics right
你知道正确地尝试做基础知识
now I don't think you know I don't I
现在我不认为 你 知道我不是
don't think robots are going to be as
不要以为机器人 会如此
autonomous in a hostile environment
在恶劣的环境中自主
as as people either think or fear
就像人们想到 或害怕一样
because of how frail they'll still be
因为 他们仍然是多么脆弱
until we get further along hi there Hey
直到我们继续沿着嗨那里 嘿
I want to ask about two things that are
我 想问 两件事情
going to probably play a big role in
可能会发挥重要作用
adoption the first is price so if you
采用第一个是价格所以，如果你
could speak to the current unit price of
可以说，以 目前单位价格
a spot many and how that you think is
很多地方以及你的想法
going to evolve over time and the second
随着时间的推移 和第二次发展
is sort of consumer psychology I felt
我觉得这是一种消费心理
like when I saw the the test at the end
就像当我看到测试末
of the robots wearing my level of
穿着我的水平的机器人
comfort with it being in my house
在 我家里安慰它
suddenly shot up
突然猛然一下
it seemed way more human so I was
它似乎更人性化， 所以我是
thinking about what kinds of experiment
思考什么样的实验
you guys were on where you what you've
你们这些人在你们所在的地方
thought about with respect to making
关于制作的想法
people more comfortable with robots
人们对机器人更舒服
working around them yeah in terms of
他们周围的工作耶 来讲
cost all I you know we're not saying
花费你所知道的我们不是说
what this thing costs yet but we will
这个东西花了多少钱，但我们会
later in the year we have reduced the
在今年晚些时候， 我们 减少了
cost of this by about a factor of 10
这个成本约为10倍
from what the first prototypes cost so
从 第一个原型成本 来看
we're making progress in terms of the
我们在 条款 方面取得进展
psychology of robots it's been very
机器人的心理学一直都是
interesting to watch you know we we got
有趣的是看着 你知道我们得到了
branded sort of as robot abusers because
因为机器人滥用者的品牌
we kick with our robot really what we
我们真的用我们的机器人踢我们
were doing was trying to show how good
正在做的是试图表明有多好
they were at balancing and we weren't we
他们在平衡，我们不是我们
didn't think we were abusing them I have
我认为我们没有滥用他们
video of me pushing on my daughter when
我推着我女儿的视频
she's one years old and actually
她一岁，实际上
knocking her over
把她撞倒了
but that wasn't my goal I wanted to kind
但这不是我的目标，我想要善良
of test out her her balance and I bet
测试她的余额我打赌
you you know if you guys have kids or
你知道你们是否有孩子或者
you're at all that you've you've done
你完成了自己所做的一切
stuff like that so but we've adjusted a
像 这样的 东西 ， 但我们调整了一个
little bit and so we don't usually push
一点点，所以我们 通常 不 推
on the robots in our videos despite the
我们的视频中的机器人尽管如此
one we showed with the hockey and the
我们用曲棍球和曲棍球展示了一个
hockey sticking hand on this thing
曲棍球在这件事上伸出手
that's why we had the banana peels as a
这就是我们将香蕉皮作为香蕉皮的原因
way to have the robot crash without us
没有我们的机器人崩溃的方法
being having our finger prints on it you
正在我们的指纹上 你
know I I guess the other data point I
知道我猜其他数据点我
have is that if you look at the likes
如果你看看喜欢的话就有
and dislikes on our YouTube videos we
和我们的YouTube视频不喜欢 我们
found a way to get the likes to dislikes
找到了让喜欢不喜欢的方法
ratio much higher by partly probably by
比率高得多，部分可能是
not looking like we're abusing the the
看起来我们没有滥用
robots there's probably a long way to go
机器人可能还有很长的路要走
to make these things really friendly and
做这些事情非常友好 ，
I have to admit there's a little
我不得不承认有一点
spirited of our cut at our company of
我们公司的裁员精神充沛
being kind of you know it's fun being
有点你知道这很有趣
bad boys in terms of you know just make
坏男孩在你而言知道 只是让
the robot do cool stuff and leave the
机器人做的很酷，离开了
the emotions to others and certainly the
对他人的情感 肯定 是
social robots that have so much going
社交机器人有这么多的 进展
into making them cute I don't know I'm
让他们变得可爱我不知道我是谁
sure we'll have marketing people working
我们肯定会让营销人员 工作
on that I don't know what else to say hi
在那我不知道还有什么 可以打招呼
general questions so in terms of
一般问题如此
research purpose or like practical
研究目的或喜欢实用
purpose so what are the reasons that we
目的是什么 原因我们
choose to investigate on these humanoid
选择调查 这些人形
robots so it seems like it cannot run as
机器人 所以它似乎 无法运行
fast as the cheetah and it also cannot
像猎豹一样快，它也不能
carry as many stuff as the big dog yeah
随身携带的东西和大狗一样多
you're you're basically saying that the
你基本上是在说那个
humanoids don't seem to be as practical
类人生物似乎并不实际
in terms of functional right so is it
在功能权方面也是如此
more efficient like like a humanoid
像人形机器人一样更有效率
robots more efficient than they start
机器人比他们开始更有效率
cheetahs and the big dogs well you know
你知道猎豹和大狗
the motivate so I don't have a good
激励所以我没有好处
answer the motivation for the DRC the
回答刚果民主共和国的 动机
DARPA Robotics Challenge which
DARPA 机器人挑战赛
humanoid robots was to say that they
类人机器人就是说 他们
wanted to use robots that could go the
想 用机器人 ，可以去
places designed for humans and and so
专为人类 而 设计的地方
that's why they used the human form and
这就是为什么他们使用人形和
I think you know there's an argument
我想你知道有一个争论
there it is true that the human form has
还有 它是真实的 人形有
a lot of complexity to it because you
因为你很复杂
have very complicated legs in the biped
在两足动物中有非常复杂的 腿
and they're supporting the weight of the
他们支持的重量
body and the arms whereas the quadrupeds
身体和手臂，而四足动物
can spread all that out so I'm
可以传播所有这些， 所以我
sympathetic to your question I don't
同情你的问题，我没有
really have an answer I can tell you
真的有答案我可以告诉你
that the public's reaction to a humanoid
公众对人形的反应
robot is off the scale compared to
机器人比较规模
anything we've done with Quadra Petro
我们用 Quadra Petro 完成的任何事情
BOTS for what that's worth so we always
我们总是为我们的价值而努力
get a lot of viewership if we show a
如果我们展示一个，可以获得很多收视率
humanoid doing something but I think
人形的做事，但我想
it's a question that we will keep
这是我们要保留的问题
addressing we are going to keep pushing
解决我们将继续 推动
on getting the humanoid to do more and
让人形机器人做更多事情
more human-like things even though we
即使我们，更像人类的东西
probably won't commercialize them as
可能不会将它们商业化为
soon as we commercialize the other stuff
我们将其他东西商业化后不久
how do you specify goals and although
你如何指定目标，尽管如此
you said earlier that it's expensive to
你之前说过它很贵
do like simulations and stuff
做模拟和东西
do you have any intentions of doing any
你有任何意图做任何事
deep reinforcement learning what was the
深层强化学习是什么
last thing I do you have any intentions
我 做的最后一件事 你有任何意图
of doing deep reinforcement learning
做深度强化学习
I'll do the last one first we I'm sure
我肯定会先做最后一次
we will use learning before too long I'm
我们将充分利用学习 不久 我
not sure whether it'll be deep
不确定它是否会很深
reinforcement learning or something else
强化学习或其他
but mostly we're interested in
但 大多数时候我们都很感兴趣
optimizing the complicated state space
优化复杂的状态空间
partitioning we do right now we use you
分区我们现在正在使用你
know people make very simple decisions
知道人们做出非常简单的决定
as to how to divide up the space and we
至于如何划分 空间和我们
think that these things could probably
认为这些事情 可能会发生
be really improved if we use the
如果我们使用它，真的会得到改善
learning approach so that's probably the
学习方法，这可能是
first place we will apply it we do a
首先我们 将应用 它我们做一个
little bit of learning here and there
在这里和那里学习一点点
but not much compared to how much
但与多少相比并不多
learning is talking about out there what
学习谈论 那里 什么
was the other question
是另一个问题
how do we specify a goal you mean to the
我们如何指定 你 的目标
robot or how do we decide as a company
机器人或我们如何决定 公司
so I don't think there's any
所以我 认为没有
across-the-board answer we write
我们写的全面答案
applications for instant for each of
每个应用程序即时
these uses so for instance in the where
这些用途，例如在哪里
we were doing the patrol route we have
我们正在做我们的巡逻路线
an application that has a UI that lets
具有 允许 的UI的应用程序
the user you know tell it the
你认识的用户告诉它
information it needs it can tell it to
它需要的信息可以告诉它
go ahead and start on the patrol and
继续前进，开始巡逻 和
things like that for for the door I
这样的事情我的门
think I think there's a button on the on
我觉得我觉得上面有一个按钮
the controller we can show you
我们可以告诉 你的控制器
afterwards if you want and you walk the
事后如果你 愿意，你就走了
robot up to the door were you steering
机器人到门口是 你 转向
it and then you press the button and
然后你按下 按钮
then it starts looking for the door
然后它开始 寻找门
handle and it goes through the hole you
处理，它穿过 你 的洞
know goes through the door but I don't
知道了，但我不知道
think these answers are fundamental I
认为这些答案是基本的
think you could do it lots of different
认为你可以做 很多 不同 的
ways
方法
you know we're working on all the
你知道我们正在全力以赴
machinery coming up from the bottom to
机器从 底部 上来 ，以
be able to do these things and then you
能够 做这些事情，然后 你
know in some case you could have it be
知道在某些情况下 ，你可以拥有它 是
buttons on an 8 on a UI it could be an
UI上的8上的按钮可能是一个
API that's accessed through some
通过一些访问的 API
higher-level ai and we just aren't
更高级别的 ai 而我们不是
sweating that part of it at this point
在这一点上冒汗了那一部分
hi so aside from locomotion I can use my
嗨，除了运动， 我可以使用 我的
body for like you know nonverbal
身体 就像你知道的非语言
communication to communicate my
沟通来沟通我的
intentions and and other such things
意图和其他此类事情
even though I'm not always aware of it
即使我并不 总是意识到 这一点
and I guess I'm wondering if this is
我想我想知道这 是不是
something that you've considered for
你考虑过的东西
these robots I think the closest we've
我认为这些机器人离 我们最近
come is having the robot go like this
有机器人这样来
after the flip which was a way of
翻转之后是 一种方式
communicating we really haven't been
沟通， 我们真的 没有
anything along those lines I'll bet you
沿着这些线路的东西 我敢打赌，你
though the people writing code can
虽然编写代码的人可以
interpret a lot of the subtleties of
解释了很多细微之处
what's you know what's working and what
你知道什么是有效的和什么的
isn't by looking at things like that but
是不是通过看这样 的 事情 ，但
the robot isn't trying to communicate
机器人没有尝试 沟通
that way
那样
I have two questions um how do you make
我有两个问题嗯，你如何
the robots really how do you make the
机器人真的是怎么做的
robots really fast how do we make them
机器人真的很快 我们 如何 制造它们
fast no my question is how did you make
快， 不，我的问题 是 你 是怎么 做的
them fast I mean like the time how we
他们快 我的意思就像我们的时间
get a lot of people who are really smart
得到很多非常 聪明的人
and good at working together with each
并善于与每个人一起工作
other at our lab and then they make
在我们的 实验室 ，然后他们做
plans and we everybody tries to stay on
计划，我们每个人都试图留下来
the plan and then you know pull it
计划，然后你知道拉它
together sometimes it doesn't go as fast
有时它不会那么快
as we like especially if we have to buy
因为我们特别喜欢，如果我们必须购买
parts from someone else and they're slow
来自其他人的部分 ，他们很慢
that happens a lot no honestly is that
发生了很多， 不是说老实说
what you mean so we don't make them that
你是什​​么意思 所以我们不会那么做
fast you know we're pretty fast you know
快 ，你知道我们是相当快的 ，你 知道
usually four or five months to build a
通常建立一个或五个月
new robot something like that but mostly
新的机器人类似的东西，但主要是
it's getting people to work together
它让人们 一起 工作
what's it what's the other question dad
什么是 爸爸的另一个问题
that question is why do the people push
那个问题就是为什么 人们会推动
the robots why did it why do they push
机器人为什么要这样做呢
why do they push we're trying the robots
为什么他们推动我们尝试机器人
are always balancing them themselves and
总是在平衡他们自己和
so we want to show that they're that
所以我们要表明他们就是 那样
they can balance by by showing that when
他们可以通过显示何时平衡
you knock them they still they don't
你敲他们，他们仍然没有
fall over they stay up on their feet so
摔倒了， 他们熬夜了
we're kind of showing off
我们有点炫耀
are you building anything why not I
你在建造什么 我为什么不是
don't know you should um let's way off
我不知道 你应该 离开
why way off where is the base I'm not
为什么离开基地我不在哪里
good at building no yes yes you are you
善于建设不是的是你是你
might think you're not well some games
可能会认为你的某些游戏并不好
there are you had to give it a try and
有你必须 尝试和
you're the right a you're the right age
你是对的，你是正确的年龄
to get started I'm six and a half
开始 我六岁 半
perfect
完善
[Applause]
[掌声]
would that I think please give the mark
我认为请给出 标记
a big hand
一个大手
thank you very much
非常 感谢
[Applause]
[掌声]